what do you remember Sobyanin saying and
что вы помните чтобы заявлял Собянин и
when can I allow a couple of questions by the way
когда можно пару вопросов кстати
Well, thank you, you asked for
разрешаю Ну благодарю Вы же спросили
permission Well, yes So I just
разрешение Ну да Значит просто вот
read the news now, something very
почитал сейчас новости что-то вот очень
similar to how, in my opinion, there was some kind of
такой как на мой взгляд пошёл какой-то
attack on your president, even Klitschko
накат на вашего президента даже Кличко
put it like this  very seriously that
там выразился так очень серьёзно что
the Dictator is the President what is going on there
Диктатор президент что там происходит
Why is this kind of KATO
Почему такой КАТО
Elite happening in your country or what does
Элит происходит у вас какой-то или что
it mean I have no idea what is
это значит понятия не имею что там
happening there but
происходит но
uh you live in your own country Yes and you and I are
ээ Вы живёте в своей стране Да и мы с
not discussing our internal
вами не обсуждаем наши внутренние
problems Yes we are discussing
проблемы Да мы обсуждаем проблемы
relationship problems  Russia and Ukraine Yes, what’s
взаимоотношения России и Украины Да что
going on with us, we figure it out for ourselves
у нас идёт это мы себе разбираемся сами
We want We have democracy, unlike
Мы хотим У нас есть демократия в отличие
you Our politicians can say what they
от вас У нас политики могут говорить про
want about the president, yes, that is, that’s the
президента то что хотят да то есть вот в
essence of democracy Yes, we can
чём и суть демократии Да мы можем с ними
agree to disagree with them  we can
соглашаться не соглашаться можем
agree with the president no, yes, you, as
соглашаться с президентом нет да вам как
slaves, don’t understand this a little. Yes,
рабам это немножко не понять Да вот
for example, you can say that the
например у вас можете сказать чтобы
governor is not this head of some
губернатор не этот глава какого-то
city Yes,
города Да говорил плохо о президенте
you can name him speaking badly about the president of the Russian Federation Well,
Российской Федерации можете назвать Ну
if there were reasons, he would probably say,
если были бы причины наверное говорил бы
look at least one  It’s just that I didn’t
смотрите вот хоть один просто я же не
ask whether there was or wasn’t at least one
спросил были бы или не был был хоть один
who
кто
said I am I’m asking if there were such codes or not
говори я сю Я спрашиваю есть или нет
I’m asking if there were people like this I’m asking if there is,
кода бы при были такие Я спрашиваю есть
look Let’s eat at the
вот смотрите Давайте есть ва на данный
moment or in general in history Ko when was the
момент или вообще в истории Ко когда
last time in history yes when  the
последний раз в истории да когда
last time in history, uh, the head of
последний раз в истории ээ глава
some city spoke badly about the
какого-то города говорил плохо о
President of the Russian
президенте Российской
Federation Well, it’s hard, you know, I don’t
Федерации Ну трудно знаете я от это не
keep track of this. Well, roughly, you remember at least
отслеживаю Ну примерно вы же помните
one. At least I’ll remember some kind of memory
хоть один Хоть какую-то вспом я допустим
about the President, no, but let’s say there were a lot of
о президенте нет но допустим много
precedents, they don’t agree there  uh, let’s
было прецедентов там не согласны там э
say
скажем
with some kind of political speech about the President
с какой-то политической па о президенте
about the President so that the head of some
о президенте чтобы вот глава какого-то
city, even in Russia, speaks out
города хоть вот в России высказался
against
против
the President. Well, you don’t know, when
Президента Ну не знаешь вот когда был
Boris Nikolayevich Yeltsin was there, they very often
Борис Николаевич Ельцин очень часто
allowed themselves to make such statements. Well, there
позволяли себе такие высказывания Ну там
was democracy there. It seems like under Yeltsin
демократия была Вроде да при ельцине
-no way, but there was democracy and there was a
как-никак но была демократия и были на
basis for this. And here it’s so ideal that it
это основание А здесь так идеально что
seems like a
вроде бы
basis povi pony I understand correctly
основание пови пони правильно понимаю
that after Yen after a year Yes, none of the
что после Ена после года Да никто из
city mayors ever spoke out
городских глав никогда не высказывался
against the
против
President No, wrong Probably Probably
Президента Нет неправильно Наверно
they did, I just don’t
Наверное высказывались просто я это не
keep track of it Yeah That is  I understand, that is,
отслеживаю Ага То есть я понял то есть
you are not just so interested, but you are
вы не просто вот так интересно да вы
tracking something there, what they say in Ukraine
что-то там отслеж что в Украине говорят
Ani, you don’t know that yours are just, well,
Ани не знаете что ваши просто ну смот
no, but you can. Let’s try.
Нет так а вот можете Давайте попробуем
Let’s try to understand why in Russia
Давайте попробуем понять почему в России
you can’t remember a single case
вы не можете вспомнить ни одного случая
of  the head of some city
чтобы глава какого-то города
spoke out against the President, I
высказывался против Президента я
can remember, for example, Yes, for example, we
например могу вспомнить Да у нас
had Poroshenko, for example, the
например был Порошенко был например
head of Lvov was there in the garden. Yes, he
глава Львова э там садове Да у него он
said that Poroshenko, for example,
говорил да что Порошенко например то-то
did something wrong then, and for example,
то тогда не так делал было да например и
we still have the EU  For some reason,
сейчас ЕС у нас всегда почему-то
city leaders can always have their own opinion
городские главы могут иметь своё мнение
and express it against, among other things, the
и высказывать её против в том числе и
central authorities, including the
центральных органов власти в том числе и
President. In Russia, we can’t
против Президента в России мы не можем
remember a single why. Well, firstly,
вспомнить ни одного почему Ну во-первых
it’s the executive branch. Yes, it’s the
это исполнительная власть Да критикует
president that criticizes us mostly  The
президента у нас в основном
legislative branch
Законодательная
there, the leaders of various factions
власть там лидеры фракций различных
speak out there,
высказываются там
well, there have been cases and not always it is
э ну бывали случаи и не всегда именно
the head of the city council of at least one
вот глава городского совета хоть одного
Well, this is the executive branch, you know, Well,
Ну это исполнительная власть понимаете
what
Ну а с чем он
will he do with it? What does it have to do with this, let’s say the president
будет Причём здесь допустим президент
that I’m sending him money I don’t know, I don’t
что деньги ему поступаю Я не знаю не
know Look, I’m just me  just Look, I
знаю Смотри я просто я просто Смотри я
understand correctly, I understand correctly
правильно понимаю я правильно понимаю
that I understand correctly what you have Yes, in the
что правильно понимаю что у вас Да в
cities, people are happy with everything and city
городах всё людей устраивает и городских
leaders are happy with everything in the
глав всё устраивает в
state. Well, probably if some
государстве Ну наверно если какие-то
revenues to the
поступления в
budget from the central budget, something
бюджет с центрального бюджета там что-то
doesn’t reach them or there are some difficulties  then they're
не доходит или какие-то сложности то
probably sorting something out somewhere,
наверно где-то разбираются что-то
correcting something,
корректируют
of course,
естественно
in which, in which, the heads of city
у которой в которой у глав городских
councils have no complaints against
Советов нет Никаких претензий к
the president. Listen, no ponies report to me.
президенту Слушай ни мне не отчитываются
They will voice the EU; they are politicians;
пони Они озвучит ЕС они политики
at least something critical
высказался хоть что-то критические в
of Putin, you know, our president
адрес Путина вы знаете у нас президент
controls the heads of these regional heads to such an extent
до того контролирует гла этих глав
that they are counted in front of him, the
регионов что они отсчитываются перед ним
president is constantly not satisfied,
президент постоянно не удовлетворён
wait, I’m not talking about the heads of regions, I’m talking
подожди я не про глав регионов говорю я
about the heads of cities, city heads of the heads And
про глав городов городские главы гла А
what about heads are you talking about city mayors  Say
что главы Вы про мэров городов Говорите
Yes, yes, the head of
Да да глава
the city, I’m not talking about the heads of the regions. Look, the
города я не про главы регионов Смотри не
heads of the regions are not appointed by the president,
главы регионов назначаются президентом
they cannot criticize him, they are his
они не могут его критиковать они его
subordinates, and the heads, here you have
подчинённые а главы вот у вас есть
local government, the head of the city, Yes, he
местное самоуправление глава города Да
is elected by the residents of the city, here you have
избирается жителями города вот у вас
Sobyanin, if I’m not mistaken, yes, yes, yes
Собянин если я не ошибаюсь да да вот да
Sobyanin at least once spoke out against Putin
Собянин хоть раз выступал против Путина
in
в
something. You know, I don’t remember this, no, well,
чём-то Вы знаете я не помню такого не ну
how do you look, you watch your
как смотрите вы смотрите новости свои
Moscow news regularly, you watch it, you read it, well, I watch it from
московские регулярно смотрите читаете Ну
time to time. I don’t remember
так периодически смотрю Я не помню
such a case
такого случая
when you read the news of your city of Moscow
чтобы новости своего города Москвы
more often than Ukrainian news, or
читаете чаще чем украинские новости или
less often than you  you know, probably less often than just
реже вы знаете наверное реже чем просто
in Yandex, let’s say so the first page
вот в Яндексе скажем так первая страница
Yes, I’m interested in further already there and
Да интересует дальше уже там есть и
Moscow, let’s say we have yes Well, let me introduce you,
Москва допустим у нас да Ну ознакомить
and since I understand correctly that you
а так раз я правильно понимаю что вы
read the news of your city less than the
новости своего города читаете меньше чем
news in Ukraine yes yes no news in
новости в Украине да да нет новости в
Ukraine I  firstly, I don’t read for one
Украине я во-первых не читаю по одной
reason because
причине потому что здесь особо
no one really writes here, sometimes you
никто не пишет вы иногда просто хорошо
can just say well what the
можете можете сказать какое было там
bloggers were saying, look, come on, let’s say
говорят блогеры смотри Дава давайте так
in the last month, in the last month,
за последний месяц за последний месяц
some kind of address from Sobyanin, can you
какое-то обращение Собянина можете
say what it
сказать о чём оно
was about?  why in general why not well
было обращение к чему вообще к чему не
put into operation some
ну ввёл в эксплуатацию там какую-то
new metro station there no not this is an
очередную станцию метро не не это вот
appeal Here you are looking Not not about this not not not this
обращение Вот вы смотрите Не не о этом
not you are looking you you
не не это не то вы смотрите вы вы
read something you know about the mayor of the
прочитали что-то вы знаете про мэра
Ukrainian city Yes capital  Yes, that he
украинского города Да столицы Да что он
said something. But what do you know that
что-то заявил А вот что вы знаете что
Sobyanin said in the last month of
Собянин заявил за последний месяц
the quarter that he said now just a second?
квартал что он заявлял сейчас секундочку
Let me just explain how I
Давайте я просто поясню откуда я это
know this. I’m including. I don’t care, I’m not
знаю Я включа Мне не важно я же не
asking where from, look at
спрашиваю откуда смотри
these exact questions. Yes, namely  Are
по именно этим вопро Да а именно вот
you interested in your Moscow
интересуетесь ли вы своими московскими
questions? Tell me, what is the last time?
вопросами Вот скажите что последний раз
And when Russian Sobyanin stated, it
И когда заявлял Собянин российский для
was simply amazing to me as a fact,
меня просто было удивительно как факт
like look again, look again, I’m
вроде ещё раз смотрите ещё раз я же
asking a
спрашиваю простой
simple question. For some reason, you are running away from a simple
вопрос Вы убегайте почему-то от простого
question. This is what you remember, what do you
вопроса вот что вы помните что вы
remember?  so that Sobyanin declares and
помните чтобы заявлял Собянин и
when what again what do you remember what
когда что ещё раз что вы помните что
Sobyanin stated and when he declared at least
заявлял Собянин и когда он заявлял хоть
something, remember, well, I’m telling you again,
что-то вспомните ну я вам ещё раз говорю
he
он с определённой
counts down to
периодичностью отсчитывается перед
citizens with a certain frequency Yes A Here is some of his
гражданами Да А Вот какое-то его
statement about new stations about the new metro are
заявление новых станций о новом метро
new  everything yes metro roads There grandmothers
новы всё да метро дороги Там бабушки
distributed yes that is about some of
раздал да то есть о каких-то заявлений
his statements that’s how politics remember his
его вот как политика помните его
statement is not just for him to say
заявление не просто чтобы он сказал что
look like this, not just for him to
смотри так смотри не просто чтобы он
say look we built something
сказал вот смотрите мы что-то построили
and so on Yes, that’s how all mayors  are doing
и так дальше Да так все мэры делают Вот
You know that the
вы знаете что заявил
mayor of Kiev and the capital in another
что-то мэр Киева да столице в другой
country said something. But you don’t know what he said, I can’t
стране А вы не знаете что заявлял я не
hear you, wait, I’ll
слышу вас подождите я вам сейчас
make an agreement with you now and he, as a person, is a manager, a
договорюсь и он как человек менеджер
city manager, at least one statement of
городской менеджер хоть одно заявление
his is not a report, not a report, but a statement
его не отчёт не отчёт а заявление
Say a statement  Say it again,
Скажите заявление Скажите ещё раз
look, you say, he makes a statement
смотрите вы говорите он делает заявление
again, look, you say, He made a report on
ещё раз смотри вы говорите Вот он отчёт
what we built, we put into
сделал что мы построили мы ввели в
operation, and at least one of his statements
эксплуатацию а заявление хоть одно его
can you say what it was about? It’s not his
можете сказать о чём было Это не его
competence. He probably doesn’t do it.
компетенция Наверно он не делает Поли ва
Look, your president, oh yours.  MR has
смотри ваш президент ой ваш МР не делал
never made any statements Yes, I don’t mean
никогда никаких заявлений Да не пом
to make any political
чтобы делал какие-то политические
statements he He supports like
заявления он Он поддерживает как во
during the elections he says stop he’s a
время выборах еди он относит стоп он
politician your mayor he’s a politician or not a
политик ваш мэр он политик или не
politician he’s a city manager he’s a politician
политик он городской менеджер он политик
No that’s not Wait He’s political
Нет это не Подождите Он от политической
no stop
нет стоп
look Manage stop stop stop him he was
смотри Управляй стоп стоп стоп его его
appointed by someone or he was elected
его назначили кто-то или его избрали
elected means he is a politician elects
избрали значит он политик избирает
means he is a politician Yes
значит он политик Да
you are elected Gra no no look him his
вы избираем Гра нет нет смотри его его
deputy he is not a politician he is an appointed
заместитель он не политик он назначенное
person and the elected one is a politician Speak he is
лицо а избранный - это политик Говори он
not he look he  elected as a result of a
не он смотрите он избран в результате
political process
политического процесса который
called elections That is, he is a politician, he is a
называется выборы То есть он политик он
politician, yes, that is, and now you say
политик да то есть а теперь вы говорите
he has no political
у него никаких политических
statements again. So let's make
заявлений ещё раз Значит мы давайте так
sure that I don't torment you anymore.
чтоб смотрите чтобы я Вас больше не
Make sure that I don't torment you anymore.
мучал Смотри чтобы я Вас больше не мучил
statements no statements  Sobyanin
заявлений никаких заявлений Собянин не
never made it, I don’t remember But at least it’s good
делал никогда я не помню А хоть хорошо
not political statements about reports
не политические заявления о отчитывается
every time not these are reports this is not a statement there are
каждый раз не это отчёты это не
reports there is a report this
заявление вот есть отчёты есть отчёт это
interview
интервью
various women anything anything everything
различны жения всё что
Connected with our
угодно всё Связано с нашим
city how unfortunate they are yes every
городом какие они несчастные да каждый
Rusak knows what and where  said Which mayor of
Русак знает что и где сказал Какой мэр
which Ukrainian city Yes, but you
какого украинского города Да но ты
live in your own Moscow and it turns out you
живёшь в своей Москве и ты оказывается
can’t remember a single statement from
не можешь вспомнить ни одного заявления
your city mayor And even now And he
своего городского главы Да и теперь А он
shouldn’t even make a statement, he’s just a
и не должен заявлять он вообще он просто
sucker He’s not a politician, he just
Он не политик он просто там короче
rolls the asphalt there in short and yes  how
асфальт катает да и всё какие они
pitiful they are, what a sting they are, they are more
жалостный какие они жало их больше
interested in what is happening in a foreign
интересует то что происходит в чужой
country than what is happening. Why? Because if
стране чем смот А почему Потому что если
they look at their country, they
они будут смотреть на свою страну им
will need to admit that they are pathetic slaves
нужно будет признать что они жалкие рабы
who do not influence anything, subscribe to
которые ни на что не влияют подпишись на
my Telegram right now OSN  and
мий Telegram прямо зараз ОСН а
the priest is even more and more
попк це дуже и дуже
polite
важливо